<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Margaret's Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://margaretleedees2.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://margaretleedees2.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-08T04:25:36-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://margaretleedees2.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Margaret Lee]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Cookin' with Git's Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/cookin-wit-git/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-08T01:02:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/cookin-wit-git</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a journey of a housewife learning to code.  Over the years, I&rsquo;ve become quite a creative chef trying to feed two very picky eaters.  Pureed cauliflower in mac-in-cheese, dates and quinoa in banana bread, and beets in raspberry sorbet.  I thought code would be sort of like cooking.  Start with a recipe, add a pinch of this and a little dash of that, and voila.   Er uh, not really.  Over the past few weeks, there are days where I feel as though I&rsquo;ve been dropped in the middle Iron Chef-Japan and I don&rsquo;t speak the language.  What? Theme ingredient is sea urchin and the course is dessert?  Hmmmmm.</p>

<p>Almost two weeks ago we started with Git.  Very cool to clone and push.  Although I am still afraid of Master.  Took time, but &lsquo;fork&rsquo; now has new meaning to me.  As do &lsquo;.slice,&rsquo; &lsquo;.split,&rsquo; &lsquo;.push,&rsquo; &lsquo;.pop&rsquo; and &lsquo;scrape&rsquo; after last week&rsquo;s Ruby binge.  Writing those words can make anyone feel like this week&rsquo;s I.C. Master Hiroyuki Sakai.</p>

<p>This week we&rsquo;re starting to blog.  For years, I purposefully put off forming accounts for Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter for fear that I would lose myself in a vortex of connecting with childhood friends vs. connecting with my own children.  Plus, what did I have to say out there on the fringes of the web?  Its a big step to be blogging.  About code nonetheless.</p>

<p>Will get to Ruby in the next blog, but for now, lets talk about the matter at hand: Git&rsquo;s Octopress.  I was just trying to get a sense of the various blog engines out there and stumbled on this brief overview which lists Octopress&rsquo;s pros.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.tealdi.com.br/2013/07/11/why-ive-chosen-octopress">http://blog.tealdi.com.br/2013/07/11/why-ive-chosen-octopress</a></p>

<p>Tealdi sums it up nicely:
&ldquo;Octopress is a simple framework designed for Jekyll, that is powering GitHub Pages. Jekyll is a simple, lightweight static site generator written in Ruby. It takes a template directory (representing the raw form of a website), runs it through Textile or Markdown and Liquid converters, and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server.&rdquo;  Wow, clear even to the foreigner!</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a neat little presentation speakerdeck.com called &ldquo;Octopress: A blogging framework for hackers&rdquo; by Akira Maeda. A propos.  A little sad but while others are probably blogging about scraping websites with Nokogiri, I&rsquo;m blogging about how to blog.  Baby steps.</p>

<p>Within the Presentation, very simple guideposts:
&ndash; Write Markdown
&ndash; Generate
&ndash; Deploy <em>I love this word and use it to launch my children off to school</em></p>

<h2>Octopress: A blogging framework for hackers</h2>

<p><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/glidenote/octopress">https://speakerdeck.com/glidenote/octopress</a></p>

<p>There are even 3rd Party Octopress Themes.  I&rsquo;m trying one out now called &lsquo;Whitespace&rsquo; by Lucas Lew.  Like?  My only problem is, I&rsquo;m still figuring out how to customize the markdown.  I&rsquo;m getting closer&hellip;. This link tells you where to go to customize other attributes in the header, aside etc., but still not quite there&hellip;..</p>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/theme/template/">http://octopress.org/docs/theme/template/</a></p>

<p>Octopress utilizes the &ldquo;usual&rdquo; Git commands to commit your source code to the blog (git add/commit/push).  I feel like I&rsquo;m getting &ldquo;bonus&rdquo; practice on Git while I learn about blogging.</p>

<p>I bid you good eating.  Next up, Ruby with guest appearance from I.C. octopodafeline.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Margaret's first post. Ever.]]></title>
    <link href="http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/margarets-first-post-ever/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T11:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/margarets-first-post-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;This is a test. For the next thirty seconds, this station will conduct a test of the Marge Octopress Blogging System. This is only a test.  BE-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-E-P.&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello world]]></title>
    <link href="http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T11:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://margaretleedees2.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
